Citizen Action of New York; Records apap341
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Legislation, 1985-2006; 7.8 cubic ft.
  - Lobbying, 1986-2006; 5.9 cubic ft.
    - Public Policy and Education Fund of New York-Proposal for Funding; A Study: Employer Based Financing of Health Care in New York, Undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Racial and Ethnic Disparity in Manhattan Jury Pools: Results of a Survey and Suggestion for Reform, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Redistricting Commission, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Re-Elect Carol Berman as State Senator, Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Reform of the State Legislative and Budgetary Process, 2002-2004 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Report of the National Leadership Coalition for Health care Reform, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Senate Republican Health Care Plan, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Senator Alfonse D'Amato Violation of Selection 1301(a) of U.S.C. 31, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Senator Bruno-Unfair Insurance Practices, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Senator Cooper's Health Care Plan, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Senator D'Amato and Health Care, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Senator Dole and Health Care, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Senator Mitchell-Health Care Legislation, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Senator Moynihan-Medical Care, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Senator Quinn-Clean-Money/Clean Election Act, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Senator Trent Lott and Council of Conservative Citizens, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Seven Warning Signs: Health Insurance at Risk, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Solid Waste, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - S.O.S. Justice, 1992; 1994; 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - State-By-State Study: Heavy Reliance on Big Checks Undercuts Bush/Cheney '04 Claims of Grassroots Support, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - State Politicians Receive 10 Times More Campaign Cash From Business than the Labor, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - State Single-Payer Option, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Statewide Candidate Questionnaire-Andrew M. Cuomo, Undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Summary of Recommendations From Poll, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Superfund Polluters, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Take Back Democracy Campaign, Undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Talking Point on the Employer/Individual Mandate, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Tax Campaign, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Tax Corp, 2002-2003 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Testimony of Joy Gould Health Care Project Director Before the New York State Insurance Department Hearing Regarding the Proposed Amended Plan of Conversion Filed By Empire Health Choice, Inc., 2002 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Testimony of Richard Kirsch (CANY)-Small Business Health Insurance, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Threat to Health Quality in Health Care Reform, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Tilting the Balanced Budget: Campaign Contributions and Special Interest Provisions in the 1997 Balanced Budget Act (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Tom Suozzi Donors, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Toxic Waste, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Trainers Training on Universal Health Care, Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Unhealthy Money Reports, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Uniting American Families Act, Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - USAction in the News, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - USAction -Presidential Politics, 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Vote for Andy Macdonald-State Senate, Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Vote for Anita Maxwell State Senate, Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Voting Guides and Voting Records, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Vote Jim Gaughran, Undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Wealth Primary: Spending New York State Legislative Election, 1996; 1998; 2000-2003 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - What You Don't Know About Congressman Boehlert's Health Care Plan May Be Hazardous to your Health, Undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Who Wants to Be A Millionaire? Executive Compensation, Lobbying, and Campaign Finance in the Industry Behind Insurance in New York State, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Will it Be Déjà Vu All Over Again? Renewing the Fight for Health Care for all, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Working Group on Electoral Democracy: A Proposal for Democratically Financed Congressional Elections, 1989-1990; 1993; 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Your Right to Know About Managed Health Care, 1997-2000 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Subject Files, 1985-2006; 2.2 cubic ft.
    This series contains documents that Citizen Action refered to when working on social, political, racial, and economic issues. This series contains news articles, information guides, workbooks, court cases, and documents related to political candidates and their campaigns. There is one folder that is restricted. Please consult an archivsit before use.
    - A National Health Plan in the U.S: The Long Term Impact on Business and the Economy, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - AFL-CIO National Health Care Reform, 1990-1991; 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - AFL-CIO Resolution on Campaign Finance Reform, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alan Sager Publications, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Alliance for Consumer Rights "Tort Reform" Qualitative Research Findings NYC, Nassau County, and Syracuse, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Amendment to the Campaign Financing Reform Act of 1999, 2000; 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Amendment to the Public Health Service Act, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Asbestos Research, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Association of the Bar of the City of New York Ad HOC Committee on Medical Malpractice-Report on Recommendation for the State of New York, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Bipartisan Campaign Reform Act, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Blue Cross and Blue Shield Service Benefit Plan, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Building Assets for Stronger Families, Better Neighborhood and Realizing the American Dream, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - California Medical Malpractice Crisis, 1992; 1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Campaign Contributions to the New York State Legislature, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Campaign Reform Project, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Carol Weir Says: Fair Health Care Everyday, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Charles Cox V. Microsoft Corporation, 1998; 2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Child Health Plus in the News, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Child Health Plus Insurance Plan and Selected Related Program Provisions, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Clean Elections in the News, 1996-2000 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Clean Elections -Maine, 2001-2004 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Clinton Health Care Plan, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Clogging the Court: the Illinois Civil Justice League's Lawsuit Abuse, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Consumer Reports, 1990; 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - The Cost of New York: Cure or Cause: How Government Mandates Limit Access to Health Insurance, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Coverage, Premium, and Household Spending Implications of Health Reform, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Democracy Project, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Economic Policy Institute-Universal Healthcare Coverage: How Do We Pay for It? By Edie Rasell, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Election and Tax Law Amendment, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Eliminating the Medicaid Asset test for Families: A Review of State Experiences, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Ellen Kennedy for Congress, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Evaluation of Child Health Plus in New York State-Summary, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Fanny Lou Harner Project, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Family Planning Advocates of New York State, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Financial Services Modernization Act, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Governor Cuomo's Town Meetings on Universal Health Care, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Governor's Health Care Advisory Board Task Force on the Clinton Health Care Plan, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Health Care in Canada (1 of 2), 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Health Care in Canada (2 of 2), 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Healthcare in Germany, 1991; Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Healthcare Polls, 1990-1992; 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Health Security For AFSCME Members, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Health Insurance and the Uninsured Background Data and Analysis, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Henry J. Kaiser Family Foundation Newsletters, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Hospital Community Benefits and Free Care Programs: An Initial Study of Seven Long Island Hospitals, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - House Health Bill-Democratic Caucus Information Packet, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - How Health Care Reform will Affect Senior Citizens, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Illusion of Prosperity: New York in the New Economy-Fiscal Policy Institute, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Investing in the People's Business: A Business Proposal for Campaign Finance Reform, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Health Insurance Association of America, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Lower East Side Speak out for Health Care, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Major Victory in the Supreme Court-Nixon V. Shrink Missouri Government PAC, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Malpractice Victims say No to Docs and HMOs, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Medical care for the Indigent, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Medical Journals on Healthcare, 1990; Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Medical Malpractice, 1987; 1990-1992; 1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Mutual Holding Company Act, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Mutual Life Legislation In the News, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Nassau County Fair Tax Plan Messages, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - The Nation, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - National Association for Social Workers-National Health Care Proposal, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - National Health Care Data, 1996; 1998-1999; 2001 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - New York City Corporate Welfare Losers, Abuser, and Cheats Identified, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health-Fairness in Asbestos Compensation Act of 2000 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - New York for Accessible Healthcare Coverage: Empire Blue Cross and Blue Shield wants to go for Profit, 1996-1997; 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - New York Health Maintenance Organization Profitability, 2001-2006 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - New York State Senate Roll Call Results, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - No Bid, No Coincidence?: Campaign Contributors and the Awarding of No-Bid Contracts in Nassau County, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - OCAW Supports "Cradle to Grave" National Health Care Pass it on, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Our Democracy, Our Airwaves, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Physicians for National Health Program for the United States (1 of 2), 1989; 1991-1994; 1996-1997; 2000 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Physicians for National Health Program for the United States (2 of 2), 1989; 1991-1994; 1996-1997; 2000 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Physician Income, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Position Paper: New Yorkers for Civil Justice Reform-Wolves in Wolves Clothing?, Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Progressive Majority, 2002-2004 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Public Campaign- Clean Money, Clean Elections, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Save our Safety Net Campaign, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Real Health Care Reform New York by District, Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Recommendations on Physicians Reimbursement Reform: Final Report, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Risking the Future: Low Income People in New York Without Health Insurance: Problems and Proposed Solution, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Rising Healthcare Costs: Causes, Implications, and Strategies, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Social Security, 1996-2001 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - State Spending, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Stringer-Leichter Campaign, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Tax Credits, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Universal New York Health Care: A Proposal, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Universal Health Care 2000 Campaign, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Voluntary Participation in Health Insurance Programs for the Uninsured, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Wendy Benchley and David Davies-Independents for Mercer County Freeholder, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Why Britain's Conservatives Support A Socialist Healthcare System, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)